Artem Timofeev

May 25, 1994

Contact

LinkedIn: Artem Timofeev

E-mail: atimofeev@tuta.io

Phone: +995 551114058

Github: https://github.com/atimofeev

As a DevOps Engineer at Devexperts, I've worked with complex trading systems and other financial solutions for top brokers, ensuring high availability, scalability, and performance. I use various AI tools on a daily basis to increase productivity and for problem-solving, and I enjoy automating routine tasks and reducing manual involvement in processes.

I have over eight years of experience in supporting and engineering roles within the fintech industry. Furthermore, I have strong skills in Linux system administration, configuration management, containerization, orchestration, monitoring, and cloud technologies. I love learning and trying new things, and I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow.

Employment

Devexperts $SRE/DevOps\ Engineer$

May 2021 — Apr 2023 Tbilisi, Georgia

- Linux platforms administration and processes automation (Ansible, Bash)
- Production platforms troubleshooting (on-call rotation)
- Ensuring systems reliability and observability (Zabbix, ELK, Prometheus)
- CI/CD pipelines setup and improvement (TeamCity, Docker)
- Infrastructure provisioning, setup and cost management (AWS, Terraform, Ansible)
- Scaling and maintenance of existing systems (Pacemaker, Terraform, Nomad)
- Firewall rules configuration (Cisco ASA)
- Web servers and proxies configuration (nginx, HAProxy)

Dec 2014 — May 2021 Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Technical Support Specialist

- Support for complex trading systems and other financial solutions for top brokers
- Communication with B2B partners from UK, USA and Australia
- Production platforms monitoring and application logs analysis (Zabbix, Grafana, ELK)
- Incident management and escalation (Jira, Slack, VoIP calls setup)
- Routine tasks automation (Bash)
- Regression testing of various platforms
- Data gathering for reporting, analytics and B2B needs (SQL, Jira, Confluence)
- Onboarding and mentoring, writing technical documentation (Confluence)

Education

2010 — 2014 Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnic University, Software engineering for computers and

computer-based systems, Specialist

Additional education: English language in scope of professional technical communication

Used Tools

Editor and Notes: Doom Emacs, Org Mode

Version Control: GitHub, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Subversion

Programming Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript

Infrastructure/Configuration: Terraform, Ansible

Containerization/Orchestration: Docker, Nomad, Kubernetes

Monitoring: Zabbix, Prometheus, Grafana, ELK

Databases: PostgreSQL, Amazon RDS, Redis

CI/CD Tools: TeamCity, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins

Cloud Platforms: AWS (VPC, IAM, S3, EC2, RDS, CodeBuild/CodeDeploy, ECR, ECS, EKS)

Other

Languages: advanced English, native Russian

Hobbies:

- Music creation: digital modular synthesizers for generative ambient and noise (VCV Rack)

- Making DYI projects: electronics, 3D modeling and 3D printing with processes automation (jinja2, GCODE)

- Moutain biking: 10 years of experience in Downhill, Enduro, Pump Track and BMX racing

- Hiking in the mountains